<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: torproject | blog.encrypted.cc]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/categories/torproject/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-30T14:41:30-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Runa A. Sandvik]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[runa.sandvik@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Did for the Tor Project in March]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/30/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-march/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T14:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/30/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-march</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Top 5 things I did this month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Started on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">#8166</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Talked to a few people about organizing Tor talks/trainings in Prague, London, Johannesburg, Cape Town, Tel Aviv, and Jerusalem. I'm hoping to have dates and details all figured out by the end of April.</p></li>
<li><p>Sent out a welcome email to our new support assistants, created RT accounts for everyone, set up help-ar@rt.tpo, help-es@rt.tpo, help-fr@rt.tpo, and help-zh@rt.tpo, updated the documentation which explains <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/support/Introduction">how to work with our support system</a>, and created <a href="https://help.torproject.org/">help.torproject.org</a> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8517">#8517</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Attended the <a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2013-March/000178.html">Rethinking censorship</a> conference in Copenhagen, the Tor developer meeting in Boston, and a <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/29/introduction-to-digital-security-with-the-cij/">digital security event</a> in London.</p></li>
<li><p>Resolved 31 tickets in the Tor help desk system. I will send out a full summary to the <a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/">tor-reports</a> mailing list in a few days.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Top 4 things I would like to do next month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Configure, test, and update <a href="https://ask.torproject.org/">ask.torproject.org</a>, our new Q&amp;A site (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8603">#8603</a>), and document the new support workflow (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8518">#8518</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Finish the forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux, document my findings, and start on either OS X or Windows.</p></li>
<li><p>Update the Tor Cloud images with new options for <em>BandwidthRate</em> and <em>BandwidthBurst</em> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7849">#7849</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8193">#8193</a>), update the step-by-step section on the Tor Cloud website with new screenshots (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8392">#8392</a>), and document the contents of the images (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7848">#7848</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Visit New York and San Francisco, and attend the <a href="http://openitp.org/?q=node/32">OpenITP Circumvention Tech Summit</a> in Hong Kong.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to digital security with the CIJ]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/29/introduction-to-digital-security-with-the-cij/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-29T10:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/29/introduction-to-digital-security-with-the-cij</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Monday the 25th of March, the Centre for Investigative Journalism in London organized a free event where journalists could <a href="http://www.tcij.org/events/2013-03-25/introduction-digital-security">learn more about digital security</a>. I was invited to speak about Tor, other speakers covered OTR, TrueCrypt, GPG, and mobile security.</p>

<p>The attendees were divided into five groups, and each speaker had 20-25 minutes with each group. I gave out USB sticks with the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en">Tor Browser Bundle</a>, the <a href="https://blog.torproject.org/blog/new-pluggable-transports-bundles-02411-alpha-flashproxy-obfsproxy">Pluggable Transports Bundle</a>, the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/dist/manual/short-user-manual_en.xhtml">short user manual</a>, and the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/findoc/2012-TorProject-Annual-Report.pdf">2012 annual report</a>.</p>

<p>I talked a bit about the history of Tor and the Tor Project, discussed a few different threats, mentioned hidden services, listed a few examples of real world use, and helped everyone get the Tor Browser Bundle up and running. I did not have access to a projector or whiteboard, so I did my best to illustrate how Tor works by drawing boxes, arrows, blobs, and stick figures on a piece of paper.</p>

<p>A number of people asked if we had some sort of document or manual explaining all the topics covered at this event. I mentioned <a href="https://securityinabox.org/">Security in a box</a> and the <a href="http://flossmanuals.net/">FLOSS Manuals</a>, but also pointed out that there is currently no single document available, that I am aware of, which explains all of these topics.</p>

<p>I have previously discussed creating such a document with the <a href="http://www.rorypecktrust.org/">Rory Peck Trust</a>, which is a London based organization that specializes in safety, security and professional development for freelance journalists. I mentioned this again when I met with them the day after the CIJ event, and I'm looking forward to seeing the end result in a few months.</p>

<p>Thanks to the <a href="http://tcij.org/">Centre for Investigative Journalism</a> for hosting the event and inviting me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I did for the Tor Project in February]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/01/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-february/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T08:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/01/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-february</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Top 5 things I did this month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Started working on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle, looked at tools such as <a href="http://developer.apple.com/library/mac/#documentation/DeveloperTools/Conceptual/InstrumentsUserGuide/Introduction/Introduction.html">Instruments</a> for OS X, and <a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/bb896645.aspx">Process Monitor</a>, <a href="https://code.google.com/p/regshot/">Regshot</a>, <a href="http://processhacker.sourceforge.net/">Process Hacker</a>, and <a href="https://www.honeynet.org/node/315">Capture BAT</a> for Windows. I believe I will also have to take differences in drives (solid state drive, hard disk drive, virtual hard disk) into account when doing this analysis. I also added a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">(#8166)</a> to the list.</p></li>
<li><p>Started working on an improved version of the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/docs/short-user-manual.html.en">short user manual</a> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/5571">#5571</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/5811">#5811</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8003">#8003</a>), but figured I would wait until we have decided if we are going to rename obfsproxy/pyobfsproxy to something that is less technical and easier to pronounce.</p></li>
<li><p>Updated a number of translations of the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/docs/short-user-manual.html.en">short user manual</a> and documented <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/translation/Introduction">how the translation process works</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Hired new translators/support assistants and drafted a welcome email with information about the different systems, accounts, escalation process, and so on. I also put together a document explaining <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/support/Introduction">how to work with our support system</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Resolved 94 tickets in the Tor help desk system (see the <a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2013-March/000163.html">tor-reports email</a> for the full summary). Thanks to Moritz, again, for taking care of the help desk while I was traveling.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Top 5 things I would like to do next month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Continue with a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle.</p></li>
<li><p>Get our new translators/support assistants started with <a href="https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/torproject/">Transifex</a> and <a href="http://www.bestpractical.com/rt/">RT</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Decide on a new name for obfsproxy/pyobfsproxy, and update the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/docs/short-user-manual.html.en">short user manual</a> and other documentation.</p></li>
<li><p>Continue working on an OS X Flash sandbox for the Tor Browser Bundle (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7008">#7008</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Travel for conferences, meetings, and other events. In March, I will be in London, Copenhagen, Boston, and Washington DC.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Training journalists in Istanbul]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/02/04/training-journalists-in-istanbul/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-04T09:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/02/04/training-journalists-in-istanbul</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After meeting with <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/02/04/meeting-with-soca-in-london/">SOCA in London</a>, I traveled to Istanbul to teach local and foreign journalists how to use Tor and Tails to keep themselves, their colleagues, and their sources safe online. I also met with the team behind <a href="http://zerodaydoc.com/">Zero Day</a>, a documentary about all things Internet security, to talk about Tor and the work that I do.</p>

<p>I met with foreign journalists on the first day and local journalists the day after. Around 30 people attended in total, and each training session lasted just over two hours. <a href="http://encrypted.cc/2013-01-28-istanbul.pdf">My presentation</a> covered threats, how you can protect your communication, local data, and external data, as well as how to use the Tor Browser Bundle and Tails. I gave out USB sticks with the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en">Tor Browser Bundle</a>, <a href="https://www.torproject.org/dist/manual/short-user-manual_en.xhtml">the short user manual</a>, and the <a href="https://cpj.org/reports/2012/04/journalist-security-guide.php">CPJ Journalist Security Guide</a>. PC users were also given USB sticks with <a href="https://tails.boum.org/">Tails</a>.</p>

<h3>Presentation</h3>

<p>The feedback has been really positive from everyone who attended, and I have been told that those who were unable to attend have been given the material I handed out. There are some things that can be improved, however:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Tor does not prevent somebody watching your Internet traffic from
learning that you're using Tor. In some cases, the fact that you are
using Tor and encrypting emails/chat/drives can be a red flag. I am
not sure how to best address this in a presentation, other than just
say that yes, it can be a red flag.</p></li>
<li><p>We talked about a few different risks, such as having your phone
tapped, your email hacked, and your home or hotel room broken into.
Having solid examples and stories helps a lot.</p></li>
<li><p>I introduced a lot of new technology in a short amount of time. Those who are not familiar with technology such as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disk_encryption">full disk encryption</a>, <a href="http://www.gnupg.org/">GPG</a>, and <a href="http://www.cypherpunks.ca/otr/">OTR</a>, would benefit from a longer and more hands-on session.</p></li>
<li><p>The presentation included screenshots of encrypted email, encrypted
chat, and the Tor Browser Bundle. Having a few videos that illustrate
how it works, what the user sees, and what the new workflow is will
make it easier to understand.</p></li>
<li><p>The presentation mentioned <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitlocker">Bitlocker</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FileVault">FileVault</a>, and <a href="http://www.truecrypt.org/">TrueCrypt</a> for full disk encryption, but did not go into details. I told everyone how to enable FileVault in OS X, and I should add these step-by-step instructions to the presentation.</p></li>
<li><p>Tor was originally designed, implemented, and deployed as a project of the U.S. Naval Research Laboratory. We also receive funding via U.S. government organizations. I covered this briefly in my presentation, but could have spent a bit more time talking about the Tor Project, Inc and why we are qualified to talk about Internet security and online anonymity.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Tails</h3>

<p>I asked a few people to try out Tails and let me know if something was
confusing, did not work, or could be improved:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Tails has <a href="https://tails.boum.org/support/known_issues/index.en.html#index1h2">very limited support</a> for Apple hardware. 23 out of 30 attendees were Mac users. I tried booting Tails on my MacBook Air, but OS X was unable to find the USB stick.</p></li>
<li><p>I am used to the Tor Browser and was surprised to see that <a href="https://check.torproject.org">check.torproject.org</a> was not the default home page.</p></li>
<li><p>Firefox will start automatically once you are connected to the
Internet. Most users did not wait for the Tails website to load
before entering another URL in the address bar. Users did not
question if they were actually using Tor.</p></li>
<li><p>One user waited for the Tails website to load, saw the green download
button and then asked if he needed to upgrade to a newer version. I
wonder if there is a way to let users know which version they are
currently using.</p></li>
<li><p>A few users seemed confused when Pidgin automatically connected to
IRC. I wonder if it would be better to have that disabled by default,
and instead take users through the process of setting up their own
accounts.</p></li>
<li><p>One user tried the email client, skipped the part where you set up
the mail servers, and tried to write an email. I wonder if there is a
way to improve this, as most users expect the mail client to work
just like the one they are used to in their normal operating system.</p></li>
<li><p>Tails uses a US keyboard layout by default. This can be confusing for
anyone with a different keyboard layout. A few users mentioned that
the tap-touchpad-to-click functionality did not work.</p></li>
<li><p>One user pointed out that there is no logout or shutdown option
available when using Tails in Windows XP mode.</p></li>
<li><p>The shutdown process can look a bit scary for anyone who is not used
to Linux, especially the part where it wipes the memory. A friendly
splash-screen of some sort would be good.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Thanks to my wonderful hosts for providing me with a place to stay,
great food, suggestions on what to see in Istanbul, and for organizing
and hosting the training sessions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting with SOCA in London]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/02/04/meeting-with-soca-in-london/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-04T09:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/02/04/meeting-with-soca-in-london</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In January I met with the <a href="http://www.soca.gov.uk/">Serious Organised Crime Agency (SOCA)</a> in London, UK. One of the challenges when dealing with online threats (cybercrime/e-crime) is understanding which leads not to follow. My goal was to help them understand what Tor is, how it works (both from a user and a relay operator point of view), and what it can and cannot do.</p>

<p>I talked about the Tor software ecosystem, including <a href="https://metrics.torproject.org/exonerator.html">ExoneraTor</a> (the website that tells you whether a given IP address was a Tor relay), and mentioned that we list all <a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/projects.html.en">official projects</a> on our website. I also mentioned Roger's trip to the <a href="https://blog.torproject.org/blog/trip-report-october-fbi-conference">FBI conference</a> in October 2012, and talked about some of the experiences we have had teaching US-based law enforcement about Tor.</p>

<p>Overall, I would say the meeting went well. They learned more about Tor and the projects we are working on, and they are aware that the protections that prevent us from figuring out what Tor users are doing - and who they are - is what's keeping all Tor users safe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
