<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: torproject | blog.encrypted.cc]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/categories/torproject/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-14T10:16:24-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Runa A. Sandvik]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[runa.sandvik@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Did for the Tor Project in April]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/05/14/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-april/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T09:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/05/14/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-april</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Top 5 things I did this month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Completed a <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/04/12/forensic-analysis-of-tor-on-linux/">forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux</a> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">#8166</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Started on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Windows (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6845">#6845</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Updated the <a href="https://cloud.torproject.org/">Tor Cloud</a> images with new options for <em>BandwidthRate</em> and <em>BandwidthBurst</em> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7849">#7849</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8193">#8193</a>), updated the step-by-step instructions on the Tor Cloud website (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8392">#8392</a>), and documented the contents of the images (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7848">#7848</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Tried to configure, test, and update <a href="https://ask.torproject.org/">ask.torproject.org</a>, our new Q&amp;A site (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8603">#8603</a>). AskBot has a few bugs here and there, and I'm not sure if it can do everything that we need and/or want it to do (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/5995">#5995</a>). I will continue this work as soon as <a href="https://ask.torproject.org/">ask.torproject.org</a> is fully set up.</p></li>
<li><p>Visited New York to be interviewed by PBS for their Off Book series, attended the International Engagement on Cyber conference in DC, visited San Francisco, and attended the OpenITP Circumvention Tech Summit in Hong Kong.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Top 5 things I would like to do next month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Configure, test, and update <a href="https://ask.torproject.org/">ask.torproject.org</a> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8603">#8603</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Document the new support workflow (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8518">#8518</a>), look at setting up translation teams on Transifex (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8717">#8717</a>), and create per language article classes (for answer templates) associated with the support help queues (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8831">#8831</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Finish the forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Windows (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6845">#6845</a>) and document my findings.</p></li>
<li><p>Start on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on OS X (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6846">#6846</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Visit Brussels and speak at NATO's <a href="http://www.nato.int/socialmedia/social-media-forum.html">Social Media Lessons Learned for International Organizations</a> discussion forum.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forensic analysis of Tor on Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/04/12/forensic-analysis-of-tor-on-linux/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T22:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/04/12/forensic-analysis-of-tor-on-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of a deliverable for two of our sponsors (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/sponsors/SponsorJ">Sponsor J</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/sponsors/SponsorL">Sponsor L</a>), I have been working on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle. In this three part series, I will summarize the most interesting or significant traces left behind after using the bundle. This post will cover Debian Linux (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">#8166</a>), part two will cover Windows 7, and part three will cover OS X 10.8.</p>

<h3>Process</h3>

<p>I set up a virtual machine with a fresh install of Debian 6.0 Squeeze,
logged in once and shut it down cleanly. I then connected the virtual
drive to another virtual machine and used <em>dd</em> to create an image of the
drive. I also used <em>hashdeep</em> to compute hashes for every file on the
drive, and <em>rsync</em> to copy all the files over to an external drive.</p>

<p>After having secured a copy of the clean virtual machine, I rebooted the
system, connected an external drive, and copied the Tor Browser Bundle
(version 2.3.25-6, 64-bit) from the external drive to my Debian home
directory. I extracted the package archive and started the Tor Browser
Bundle by running <em>./start-tor-browser</em> inside the Tor Browser directory.</p>

<p>Once the Tor Browser was up and running, I browsed to a few pages, read
a few paragraphs here and there, clicked on a few links, and then shut
it down by closing the Tor Browser and clicking on the <em>Exit</em>-button in
Vidalia. The Tor Browser did not crash and I did not see any error
messages. I deleted the Tor Browser directory and the tarball using
<em>rm -rf</em>.</p>

<p>I repeated the steps with <em>dd</em>, <em>hashdeep</em>, and <em>rsync</em> to create a copy of
the tainted virtual machine.</p>

<h3>Results</h3>

<p>Using <em>hashdeep</em>, I compared the hashes from the tainted virtual machine
against the hashes from the clean virtual machine: <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/files/debian_changed_files.txt">68 files</a>
had a hash that did not match any of the hashes in the clean set. The
most interesting files are:</p>

<p><strong>~/.local/share/gvfs-metadata/home</strong>: contains the filename of
the Tor Browser Bundle tarball:
<em>tor-browser-gnu-linux-x86_64-2.3.25-5-dev-en-US.tar.gz</em>. GVFS is the
virtual filesystem for the GNOME desktop, so this result will probably
vary depending on the window manager used. I have created
<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8695">#8695</a> for this issue.</p>

<p><strong>~/.xsession-errors</strong>: contains the following string: <em>"Window
manager warning: Buggy client sent a _NET_ACTIVE_WINDOW message with a
timestamp of 0 for 0x3800089 (Tor Browse)"</em>. It is worth noting that a
file named <em>.xsession-errors.old</em> could also exist. I have created
<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8696">#8696</a> for this issue.</p>

<p><strong>~/.bash_history</strong>: contains a record of commands typed into
the terminal. I started the Tor Browser Bundle from the command line, so
this file contains lines such as <em>./start-tor-browser</em>. I have created
<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8697">#8697</a> for this
issue.</p>

<p><strong>/var/log/daemon.log</strong>, <strong>/var/log/syslog</strong>, <strong>/var/log/kern.log</strong>,
<strong>/var/log/messages</strong>: contains information about attached devices. I
had an external drive attached to the virtual machine, so these files
contain lines such as <em>"Mounted /dev/sdb1 (Read-Write, label "THA", NTFS
3.1)"</em> and <em>"Initializing USB Mass Storage driver..."</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Did for the Tor Project in March]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/30/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-march/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T14:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/30/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-march</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Top 5 things I did this month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Started on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">#8166</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Talked to a few people about organizing Tor talks/trainings in Prague, London, Johannesburg, Cape Town, Tel Aviv, and Jerusalem. I'm hoping to have dates and details all figured out by the end of April.</p></li>
<li><p>Sent out a welcome email to our new support assistants, created RT accounts for everyone, set up help-ar@rt.tpo, help-es@rt.tpo, help-fr@rt.tpo, and help-zh@rt.tpo, updated the documentation which explains <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/support/Introduction">how to work with our support system</a>, and created <a href="https://help.torproject.org/">help.torproject.org</a> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8517">#8517</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Attended the <a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2013-March/000178.html">Rethinking censorship</a> conference in Copenhagen, the Tor developer meeting in Boston, and a <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/29/introduction-to-digital-security-with-the-cij/">digital security event</a> in London.</p></li>
<li><p>Resolved 31 tickets in the Tor help desk system. I will send out a full summary to the <a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/">tor-reports</a> mailing list in a few days.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Top 4 things I would like to do next month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Configure, test, and update <a href="https://ask.torproject.org/">ask.torproject.org</a>, our new Q&amp;A site (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8603">#8603</a>), and document the new support workflow (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8518">#8518</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Finish the forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux, document my findings, and start on either OS X or Windows.</p></li>
<li><p>Update the Tor Cloud images with new options for <em>BandwidthRate</em> and <em>BandwidthBurst</em> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7849">#7849</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8193">#8193</a>), update the step-by-step section on the Tor Cloud website with new screenshots (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8392">#8392</a>), and document the contents of the images (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7848">#7848</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Visit New York and San Francisco, and attend the <a href="http://openitp.org/?q=node/32">OpenITP Circumvention Tech Summit</a> in Hong Kong.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to digital security with the CIJ]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/29/introduction-to-digital-security-with-the-cij/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-29T10:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/29/introduction-to-digital-security-with-the-cij</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Monday the 25th of March, the Centre for Investigative Journalism in London organized a free event where journalists could <a href="http://www.tcij.org/events/2013-03-25/introduction-digital-security">learn more about digital security</a>. I was invited to speak about Tor, other speakers covered OTR, TrueCrypt, GPG, and mobile security.</p>

<p>The attendees were divided into five groups, and each speaker had 20-25 minutes with each group. I gave out USB sticks with the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en">Tor Browser Bundle</a>, the <a href="https://blog.torproject.org/blog/new-pluggable-transports-bundles-02411-alpha-flashproxy-obfsproxy">Pluggable Transports Bundle</a>, the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/dist/manual/short-user-manual_en.xhtml">short user manual</a>, and the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/findoc/2012-TorProject-Annual-Report.pdf">2012 annual report</a>.</p>

<p>I talked a bit about the history of Tor and the Tor Project, discussed a few different threats, mentioned hidden services, listed a few examples of real world use, and helped everyone get the Tor Browser Bundle up and running. I did not have access to a projector or whiteboard, so I did my best to illustrate how Tor works by drawing boxes, arrows, blobs, and stick figures on a piece of paper.</p>

<p>A number of people asked if we had some sort of document or manual explaining all the topics covered at this event. I mentioned <a href="https://securityinabox.org/">Security in a box</a> and the <a href="http://flossmanuals.net/">FLOSS Manuals</a>, but also pointed out that there is currently no single document available, that I am aware of, which explains all of these topics.</p>

<p>I have previously discussed creating such a document with the <a href="http://www.rorypecktrust.org/">Rory Peck Trust</a>, which is a London based organization that specializes in safety, security and professional development for freelance journalists. I mentioned this again when I met with them the day after the CIJ event, and I'm looking forward to seeing the end result in a few months.</p>

<p>Thanks to the <a href="http://tcij.org/">Centre for Investigative Journalism</a> for hosting the event and inviting me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I did for the Tor Project in February]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/01/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-february/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T08:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/01/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-february</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Top 5 things I did this month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Started working on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle, looked at tools such as <a href="http://developer.apple.com/library/mac/#documentation/DeveloperTools/Conceptual/InstrumentsUserGuide/Introduction/Introduction.html">Instruments</a> for OS X, and <a href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/bb896645.aspx">Process Monitor</a>, <a href="https://code.google.com/p/regshot/">Regshot</a>, <a href="http://processhacker.sourceforge.net/">Process Hacker</a>, and <a href="https://www.honeynet.org/node/315">Capture BAT</a> for Windows. I believe I will also have to take differences in drives (solid state drive, hard disk drive, virtual hard disk) into account when doing this analysis. I also added a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">(#8166)</a> to the list.</p></li>
<li><p>Started working on an improved version of the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/docs/short-user-manual.html.en">short user manual</a> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/5571">#5571</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/5811">#5811</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8003">#8003</a>), but figured I would wait until we have decided if we are going to rename obfsproxy/pyobfsproxy to something that is less technical and easier to pronounce.</p></li>
<li><p>Updated a number of translations of the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/docs/short-user-manual.html.en">short user manual</a> and documented <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/translation/Introduction">how the translation process works</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Hired new translators/support assistants and drafted a welcome email with information about the different systems, accounts, escalation process, and so on. I also put together a document explaining <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/support/Introduction">how to work with our support system</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Resolved 94 tickets in the Tor help desk system (see the <a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2013-March/000163.html">tor-reports email</a> for the full summary). Thanks to Moritz, again, for taking care of the help desk while I was traveling.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Top 5 things I would like to do next month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Continue with a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle.</p></li>
<li><p>Get our new translators/support assistants started with <a href="https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/torproject/">Transifex</a> and <a href="http://www.bestpractical.com/rt/">RT</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>Decide on a new name for obfsproxy/pyobfsproxy, and update the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/docs/short-user-manual.html.en">short user manual</a> and other documentation.</p></li>
<li><p>Continue working on an OS X Flash sandbox for the Tor Browser Bundle (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7008">#7008</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Travel for conferences, meetings, and other events. In March, I will be in London, Copenhagen, Boston, and Washington DC.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
