<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: torproject | blog.encrypted.cc]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/categories/torproject/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-25T18:11:38-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Runa A. Sandvik]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[runa.sandvik@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forensic Analysis of Tor on Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/05/20/forensic-analysis-of-tor-on-windows/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-20T11:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/05/20/forensic-analysis-of-tor-on-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of a deliverable for two Tor Project sponsors (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/sponsors/SponsorJ">Sponsor J</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/sponsors/SponsorL">Sponsor L</a>), I have been working on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle. In this three part series, I will summarize the most interesting or significant traces left behind after using the bundle, deleting it, and then shutting down the computer. Part one <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/04/12/forensic-analysis-of-tor-on-linux/">covered</a> Debian Linux (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">#8166</a>), this part will cover Windows 7 (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6845">#6845</a>), and part three will cover OS X 10.8 (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6846">#6846</a>).</p>

<h3>Process</h3>

<p>I set up a virtual machine with a fresh install of Windows 7, logged in
with the default admin account, installed available updates, and shut it
down cleanly. I connected the virtual drive to another virtual machine,
used <em>hashdeep</em> to compute hashes for every file on the drive, and then
<em>rsync</em> to copy all the files over to an external drive.</p>

<p>After having secured a copy of the clean virtual machine, I rebooted the
system, connected an external drive, and copied the Tor Browser Bundle
(version 2.3.25-6, 64-bit) from the external drive to the <em>Desktop</em>. I
extracted the package archive by clicking on the file, then started the
Tor Browser Bundle by going into the <em>Tor Browser</em> folder and clicking
on <em>Start Tor Browser.exe</em>.</p>

<p>Once the Tor Browser was up and running, I browsed to a few pages, read
a few paragraphs here and there, clicked on a few links, and then shut
it down by closing the Tor Browser and clicking on the <em>Exit</em>-button in
Vidalia. The Tor Browser did not crash and I did not see any error
messages. I deleted the Tor Browser folder and the package archive by
moving the folder and the archive into the <em>Recycle Bin</em>, right-clicking
on it and choosing <em>Empty Recycle Bin</em>.</p>

<p>I repeated the steps with hashdeep and rsync to create a copy of
the tainted virtual machine. I also used
<a href="http://www.thebaskins.com/main/component/content/article/15-work/60-noriben-your-personal-portable-malware-sandbox">Noriben</a>,
written by Brian Baskin, to create a report of everything the Tor
Browser Bundle did while it was running.</p>

<h3>Results</h3>

<p>Using hashdeep, I compared the hashes from the tainted virtual machine
against the hashes from the clean virtual machine: <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/files/windows_changed_files.txt">256 files</a>
have hashes that do not match any of the hashes in the clean set.
Additionally, the <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/files/noriben.txt">Noriben output</a>
shows the Tor Browser Bundle create, edit, and remove a bunch of files.</p>

<p>I have sorted the most interesting findings into different groups,
depending on the location, how they were created, and so on.
Windows 7 has <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/3ak841sy.aspx#isolated_storage_locations">built-in symbolic links</a>
designed for backward compatibility, which is why Noriben and hashdeep
list the same files in different locations.</p>

<h4>Prefetch</h4>

<p>Windows keeps track of the way the system starts and which programs the
user commonly opens. This information is saved as a number of small
files in the prefetch folder:</p>

<ul>
<li>C:\Windows\Prefetch\START TOR BROWSER.EXE-F5557FAC.pf</li>
<li>C:\Windows\Prefetch\TBB-FIREFOX.EXE-350502C5.pf</li>
<li>C:\Windows\Prefetch\TOR-BROWSER-2.3.25-6_EN-US.EX-1354A499.pf</li>
<li>C:\Windows\Prefetch\TOR.EXE-D7159D93.pf</li>
<li>C:\Windows\Prefetch\VIDALIA.EXE-5167E0BC.pf</li>
</ul>


<p>The following cache files are most likely similar to prefetch files and
might contain traces of the Tor Browser Bundle:</p>

<ul>
<li>C:\Users\runa\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\Caches\cversions.1.db</li>
<li>C:\Users\runa\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\Caches{AFBF9F1A-8EE8-4C77-AF34-C647E37CA0D9}.1.ver0x0000000000000006.db</li>
<li>C:\Windows\AppCompat\Programs\RecentFileCache.bcf</li>
</ul>


<p>I have created <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8916">#8916</a> for this issue.</p>

<h4>SetupAPI</h4>

<p>SetupAPI and the Plug and Play (PnP) manager write entries to
<em>SetupAPI.dev.log</em> and <em>SetupAPI.app.log</em> about operations that install
devices and drivers. The following files contain information about the
attached external drive:</p>

<ul>
<li>C:\Windows\inf\setupapi.dev.log</li>
<li>C:\Windows\System32\DriverStore\FileRepository\usbstor.inf_amd64_ neutral_0725c2806a159a9d\usbstor.PNF</li>
</ul>


<h4>Thumbnail Cache</h4>

<p>Windows stores thumbnails of graphics files, and certain document and
movie files, in Thumbnail Cache files. The following files contain the
Onion Logo icon associated with the Tor Browser Bundle:</p>

<ul>
<li>C:\Users\Runa\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\Explorer\thumbcache_32.db</li>
<li>C:\Users\Runa\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\Explorer\thumbcache_96.db</li>
<li>C:\Users\Runa\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\Explorer\thumbcache_256.db</li>
</ul>


<p>Other Thumbnail Cache files, such as <em>thumbcache_1024.db</em>,
<em>thumbcache_sr.db</em>, <em>thumbcache_idx.db</em>, and <em>IconCache.db</em>, may also
contain the Onion Logo icon. I have created
<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8921">#8921</a> for this issue.</p>

<h4>Windows Defender</h4>

<p>Windows Defender is the default anti-virus software on Windows 7.
Windows Defender will write log files to the following location:</p>

<ul>
<li>C:\ProgramData\Microsoft\Windows Defender\Support\</li>
</ul>


<p>The log files will contain traces of the Tor Browser Bundle if Windows
Defender ever decides to flag it as malware. This is true for any
anti-virus software.</p>

<h4>Windows Error Reporting (WER)</h4>

<p>Windows Error Reporting (WER) captures and logs information about
software crashes and other issues. I found information about the
attached external drive in the following file:</p>

<ul>
<li>C:\Users\runa\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\WER\ReportQueue\NonCritical_x64_ 84cd279a5e83221bfa7edcb36665592c1974e4_cab_0b21673a/DMI671B.tmp.log.xml</li>
</ul>


<p>The logs will probably contain traces of the Tor Browser Bundle if any
part of the bundle, such as the Tor Browser or Vidalia, ever hangs or
crashes.</p>

<h4>Windows Event Log</h4>

<p>The following two event logs contain information about the attached
external drive:</p>

<ul>
<li>C:\Windows\System32\winevt\Logs\Application.evtx</li>
<li>C:\Windows\System32\winevt\Logs\System.evtx</li>
</ul>


<h4>Windows Paging File</h4>

<p>Microsoft Windows uses a paging file, called <em>pagefile.sys</em>, to store
frames of memory that do not currently fit into physical memory. The
file <em>C:\pagefile.sys</em> contains information about the attached external
drive, as well as the filename for the Tor Browser Bundle executable. I
have created <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8918">#8918</a> for this issue.</p>

<h4>Windows Registry</h4>

<p>The Windows Registry is a databse that stores various configuration
settings and options for the operating system. <em>HKEY_CURRENT_USER</em>,
abbreviated <em>HKCU</em>, stores settings that are specific to the currently
logged-in user. Each user's settings are stored in files called
<em>NTUSER.DAT</em> and <em>UsrClass.dat</em>.</p>

<p>The path to the Tor Browser Bundle executable is listed in the following
two files:</p>

<ul>
<li>C:\Users\runa\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\UsrClass.dat</li>
<li>C:\Users\runa\AppData\Local\Microsoft\Windows\UsrClass.dat.LOG1</li>
</ul>


<p>I did not find traces of the Tor Browser Bundle in any of the
<em>NTUSER.DAT</em> files. I have created
<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8919">#8919</a> for
this issue.</p>

<p>Additionally, the output from Noriben indicates that the Tor Browser
Bundle touches the registry by creating keys and setting values. The
following value points to the Tor Browser Bundle executable on the
attached external drive:</p>

<ul>
<li>[Set Value] Explorer.EXE:1196 > HKCU\Software\Classes\Local Settings\Software\Microsoft\Windows\Shell\MuiCache\E:\tor-browser-2.3.25-6_en-US.exe  =  7z SFX</li>
</ul>


<p>The output also makes it look like the Tor Browser Bundle adds the following keys and values:</p>

<ul>
<li>[Set Value] tbb-firefox.exe:1124 > HKCU\Software\Classes\Local Settings\MuiCache\11\52C64B7E\LanguageList  =  en-US, en</li>
<li>[CreateKey] tbb-firefox.exe:1124 > HKCU\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Explorer\UserAssist{CEBFF5CD-ACE2-4F4F-9178-9926F41749EA}</li>
<li>[CreateKey] tbb-firefox.exe:1124 > HKCU\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Explorer\UserAssist{CEBFF5CD-ACE2-4F4F-9178-9926F41749EA}\Count</li>
<li>[CreateKey] tbb-firefox.exe:1124 > HKCU\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Explorer\UserAssist{F4E57C4B-2036-45F0-A9AB-443BCFE33D9F}</li>
<li>[CreateKey] tbb-firefox.exe:1124 > HKCU\Software\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Explorer\UserAssist{F4E57C4B-2036-45F0-A9AB-443BCFE33D9F}\Count</li>
</ul>


<p>I found that these keys and values are present on a clean Windows 7 system
where the Tor Browser Bundle has never been used. I also downloaded and tested
the German version of the Tor Browser Bundle to make sure that the
<em>LanguageList</em> value does not represent the language of the Tor Browser Bundle.</p>

<h4>Windows Search</h4>

<p>Windows Search, which is enabled by default, builds a full-text index of
files on the computer. One component of Windows Search is the Indexer,
which crawls the file system on initial setup, and then listens for file
system notifications to index changed files. Windows Search writes a number of
files to the following location:</p>

<ul>
<li>C:\ProgramData\Microsoft\Search\Data\Applications\Windows\</li>
</ul>


<p>I have not found a way to read the Windows Search database files, but I
would say it is likely that Windows Search picked up the Tor Browser
Bundle at some point. I have created
<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8920">#8920</a> for this issue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Did for the Tor Project in April]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/05/14/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-april/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T09:57:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/05/14/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-april</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Top 5 things I did this month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Completed a <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/04/12/forensic-analysis-of-tor-on-linux/">forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux</a> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">#8166</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Started on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Windows (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6845">#6845</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Updated the <a href="https://cloud.torproject.org/">Tor Cloud</a> images with new options for <em>BandwidthRate</em> and <em>BandwidthBurst</em> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7849">#7849</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8193">#8193</a>), updated the step-by-step instructions on the Tor Cloud website (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8392">#8392</a>), and documented the contents of the images (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7848">#7848</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Tried to configure, test, and update <a href="https://ask.torproject.org/">ask.torproject.org</a>, our new Q&amp;A site (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8603">#8603</a>). AskBot has a few bugs here and there, and I'm not sure if it can do everything that we need and/or want it to do (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/5995">#5995</a>). I will continue this work as soon as <a href="https://ask.torproject.org/">ask.torproject.org</a> is fully set up.</p></li>
<li><p>Visited New York to be interviewed by PBS for their Off Book series, attended the International Engagement on Cyber conference in DC, visited San Francisco, and attended the OpenITP Circumvention Tech Summit in Hong Kong.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Top 5 things I would like to do next month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Configure, test, and update <a href="https://ask.torproject.org/">ask.torproject.org</a> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8603">#8603</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Document the new support workflow (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8518">#8518</a>), look at setting up translation teams on Transifex (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8717">#8717</a>), and create per language article classes (for answer templates) associated with the support help queues (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8831">#8831</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Finish the forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Windows (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6845">#6845</a>) and document my findings.</p></li>
<li><p>Start on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on OS X (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6846">#6846</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Visit Brussels and speak at NATO's <a href="http://www.nato.int/socialmedia/social-media-forum.html">Social Media Lessons Learned for International Organizations</a> discussion forum.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forensic analysis of Tor on Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/04/12/forensic-analysis-of-tor-on-linux/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T22:05:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/04/12/forensic-analysis-of-tor-on-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of a deliverable for two of our sponsors (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/sponsors/SponsorJ">Sponsor J</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/sponsors/SponsorL">Sponsor L</a>), I have been working on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle. In this three part series, I will summarize the most interesting or significant traces left behind after using the bundle. This post will cover Debian Linux (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">#8166</a>), part two will cover Windows 7, and part three will cover OS X 10.8.</p>

<h3>Process</h3>

<p>I set up a virtual machine with a fresh install of Debian 6.0 Squeeze,
logged in once and shut it down cleanly. I then connected the virtual
drive to another virtual machine and used <em>dd</em> to create an image of the
drive. I also used <em>hashdeep</em> to compute hashes for every file on the
drive, and <em>rsync</em> to copy all the files over to an external drive.</p>

<p>After having secured a copy of the clean virtual machine, I rebooted the
system, connected an external drive, and copied the Tor Browser Bundle
(version 2.3.25-6, 64-bit) from the external drive to my Debian home
directory. I extracted the package archive and started the Tor Browser
Bundle by running <em>./start-tor-browser</em> inside the Tor Browser directory.</p>

<p>Once the Tor Browser was up and running, I browsed to a few pages, read
a few paragraphs here and there, clicked on a few links, and then shut
it down by closing the Tor Browser and clicking on the <em>Exit</em>-button in
Vidalia. The Tor Browser did not crash and I did not see any error
messages. I deleted the Tor Browser directory and the tarball using
<em>rm -rf</em>.</p>

<p>I repeated the steps with <em>dd</em>, <em>hashdeep</em>, and <em>rsync</em> to create a copy of
the tainted virtual machine.</p>

<h3>Results</h3>

<p>Using <em>hashdeep</em>, I compared the hashes from the tainted virtual machine
against the hashes from the clean virtual machine: <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/files/debian_changed_files.txt">68 files</a>
had a hash that did not match any of the hashes in the clean set. The
most interesting files are:</p>

<p><strong>~/.local/share/gvfs-metadata/home</strong>: contains the filename of
the Tor Browser Bundle tarball:
<em>tor-browser-gnu-linux-x86_64-2.3.25-5-dev-en-US.tar.gz</em>. GVFS is the
virtual filesystem for the GNOME desktop, so this result will probably
vary depending on the window manager used. I have created
<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8695">#8695</a> for this issue.</p>

<p><strong>~/.xsession-errors</strong>: contains the following string: <em>"Window
manager warning: Buggy client sent a _NET_ACTIVE_WINDOW message with a
timestamp of 0 for 0x3800089 (Tor Browse)"</em>. It is worth noting that a
file named <em>.xsession-errors.old</em> could also exist. I have created
<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8696">#8696</a> for this issue.</p>

<p><strong>~/.bash_history</strong>: contains a record of commands typed into
the terminal. I started the Tor Browser Bundle from the command line, so
this file contains lines such as <em>./start-tor-browser</em>. I have created
<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8697">#8697</a> for this
issue.</p>

<p><strong>/var/log/daemon.log</strong>, <strong>/var/log/syslog</strong>, <strong>/var/log/kern.log</strong>,
<strong>/var/log/messages</strong>: contains information about attached devices. I
had an external drive attached to the virtual machine, so these files
contain lines such as <em>"Mounted /dev/sdb1 (Read-Write, label "THA", NTFS
3.1)"</em> and <em>"Initializing USB Mass Storage driver..."</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Did for the Tor Project in March]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/30/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-march/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T14:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/30/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-march</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Top 5 things I did this month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Started on a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8166">#8166</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Talked to a few people about organizing Tor talks/trainings in Prague, London, Johannesburg, Cape Town, Tel Aviv, and Jerusalem. I'm hoping to have dates and details all figured out by the end of April.</p></li>
<li><p>Sent out a welcome email to our new support assistants, created RT accounts for everyone, set up help-ar@rt.tpo, help-es@rt.tpo, help-fr@rt.tpo, and help-zh@rt.tpo, updated the documentation which explains <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/support/Introduction">how to work with our support system</a>, and created <a href="https://help.torproject.org/">help.torproject.org</a> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8517">#8517</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Attended the <a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2013-March/000178.html">Rethinking censorship</a> conference in Copenhagen, the Tor developer meeting in Boston, and a <a href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/29/introduction-to-digital-security-with-the-cij/">digital security event</a> in London.</p></li>
<li><p>Resolved 31 tickets in the Tor help desk system. I will send out a full summary to the <a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/">tor-reports</a> mailing list in a few days.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Top 4 things I would like to do next month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Configure, test, and update <a href="https://ask.torproject.org/">ask.torproject.org</a>, our new Q&amp;A site (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8603">#8603</a>), and document the new support workflow (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8518">#8518</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Finish the forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on Linux, document my findings, and start on either OS X or Windows.</p></li>
<li><p>Update the Tor Cloud images with new options for <em>BandwidthRate</em> and <em>BandwidthBurst</em> (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7849">#7849</a>, <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8193">#8193</a>), update the step-by-step section on the Tor Cloud website with new screenshots (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8392">#8392</a>), and document the contents of the images (<a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7848">#7848</a>).</p></li>
<li><p>Visit New York and San Francisco, and attend the <a href="http://openitp.org/?q=node/32">OpenITP Circumvention Tech Summit</a> in Hong Kong.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction to digital security with the CIJ]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/29/introduction-to-digital-security-with-the-cij/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-29T10:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/03/29/introduction-to-digital-security-with-the-cij</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Monday the 25th of March, the Centre for Investigative Journalism in London organized a free event where journalists could <a href="http://www.tcij.org/events/2013-03-25/introduction-digital-security">learn more about digital security</a>. I was invited to speak about Tor, other speakers covered OTR, TrueCrypt, GPG, and mobile security.</p>

<p>The attendees were divided into five groups, and each speaker had 20-25 minutes with each group. I gave out USB sticks with the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en">Tor Browser Bundle</a>, the <a href="https://blog.torproject.org/blog/new-pluggable-transports-bundles-02411-alpha-flashproxy-obfsproxy">Pluggable Transports Bundle</a>, the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/dist/manual/short-user-manual_en.xhtml">short user manual</a>, and the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/findoc/2012-TorProject-Annual-Report.pdf">2012 annual report</a>.</p>

<p>I talked a bit about the history of Tor and the Tor Project, discussed a few different threats, mentioned hidden services, listed a few examples of real world use, and helped everyone get the Tor Browser Bundle up and running. I did not have access to a projector or whiteboard, so I did my best to illustrate how Tor works by drawing boxes, arrows, blobs, and stick figures on a piece of paper.</p>

<p>A number of people asked if we had some sort of document or manual explaining all the topics covered at this event. I mentioned <a href="https://securityinabox.org/">Security in a box</a> and the <a href="http://flossmanuals.net/">FLOSS Manuals</a>, but also pointed out that there is currently no single document available, that I am aware of, which explains all of these topics.</p>

<p>I have previously discussed creating such a document with the <a href="http://www.rorypecktrust.org/">Rory Peck Trust</a>, which is a London based organization that specializes in safety, security and professional development for freelance journalists. I mentioned this again when I met with them the day after the CIJ event, and I'm looking forward to seeing the end result in a few months.</p>

<p>Thanks to the <a href="http://tcij.org/">Centre for Investigative Journalism</a> for hosting the event and inviting me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
