<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: torproject | blog.encrypted.cc]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/categories/torproject/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-02T17:57:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Runa A. Sandvik]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[runa.sandvik@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I did for the Tor Project in January]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/02/02/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-january/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-02T17:29:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.encrypted.cc/blog/2013/02/02/what-i-did-for-the-tor-project-in-january</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of each month, I send an email to the
<a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/">tor-reports</a>
mailing list describing what I did the previous month. I figured that
re-posting this status update here would be a good way to start my blog.</p>

<h3>Top 4 things I did this month</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Started working on an OS X Flash sandbox for the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en">Tor Browser Bundle</a> <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7008">(#7008)</a>. Building TBB on OS X was a bit of a challenge <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7964">(#7964)</a> and I also ran into a bug with the Tor Browser crashing whenever I visit certain Flash sites <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/8129">(#8129)</a>.</p></li>
<li><p>I interviewed 26 candidates for the <a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/jobs-translatorsupport.html.en">translator/support assistant position(s)</a>. All the interviews were done via email and I spent a lot of time reviewing the answers I received. I hope we can move forward and hire support assistants in February.</p></li>
<li><p>I gave a talk about Tor and the Arab Spring at <a href="http://www.hacdc.org/">HacDC</a>. I met with researchers in DC and listened to talks about privacy, stylometry, analysis of onion routing security, and an evaluation of relay
selection in Tor. I attended a meeting with the US Drug Enforcement Agency (DEA) where Andrew talked about all things Tor. I traveled to London and Istanbul (trip reports will be published on Monday).</p></li>
<li><p>I resolved 204 tickets in the Tor help desk system (see the <a href="https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-reports/2013-February/000148.html">tor-reports email</a> for the full summary). I'd like to thank Moritz for taking care of the help desk while I was traveling.</p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Top 5 things I would like to do next month:</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Begin a forensic analysis of the Tor Browser Bundle on OS X 10.8 <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6846">(#6846)</a> and Windows 7 <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/6845">(#6845)</a>. I still need to figure out if we are adding Linux to the list (the <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/org/sponsors/SponsorJ">sponsor page</a> says yes, but we have no ticket for it).</p></li>
<li><p>Continue working on an OS X Flash sandbox for the Tor Browser Bundle <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7008">(#7008)</a>. I should be able to continue with this even if the browser is crashing on certain sites.</p></li>
<li><p>I have a few Trac tickets related to translations and <a href="https://www.torproject.org/docs/short-user-manual.html.en">the short user manual</a>. I also want to properly document how the translation process works (from adding a new translation resource to pulling down new or updated translations).</p></li>
<li><p>Help new translators/support assistants get started with <a href="https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/torproject/">Transifex</a> and <a href="http://www.bestpractical.com/rt/">RT</a>. I started writing an <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/support/Introduction">introduction</a> to the Tor help desk system and should make sure this is complete and up to date.</p></li>
<li><p>Attend <a href="http://www.shmoocon.org/">Shmoocon</a> and go on vacation.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
